and the title of the sermon the darkness
of God I know that for many people here
you see this title and it's you get a
dark feeling you get this kind of like
the darkness of God that that doesn't
sound too good that doesn't sound like
an inviting idea but I'm gonna share
some thoughts with you through this
message that hopefully will lead you to
see the amazing love of God because
that's what we're going to be talking
about today
the amazing love of God so let's begin
we're gonna go to our first verse it's
found in Exodus chapter 19 and beginning
with verse 9 this as a backdrop this is
dealing with the children of Israel who
have just come out of captivity they've
just come out of Egypt and God is about
to speak to them at Mount Sinai and in
Exodus 19 verse 9 the Bible says and the
Lord said unto Moses lo I come unto thee
in a thick cloud that the people may
hear when I speak with thee and believe
thee forever
and Moses told the words of the people
unto the Lord so watch what's happening
here God is coming to the children of
Israel in what in a thick cloud I want
you to imagine that cloud imagine being
one of the children of Israel in that
time and you're seeing this mountain and
you're seeing this cloud descend upon
the mountain and it's a thick cloud it's
like nothing you have ever seen
before reading on in Exodus chapter 20
verse 19 through 21 the Bible says and
they said unto Moses speak with us and
we will hear but let not God speak with
us less we die and Moses said unto the
people fear not fear not don't be afraid
of this thick darkness I want you to get
the idea that they are terrified of what
they're seeing this thick
almost incomprehensible darkness and
they were afraid of it but Moses says
fear not for God has come to prove you
and that is fear maybe before your face
is that you sin not and the Moses and
the people stood afar off and Moses June
near unto the thick darkness where God
was now I know when you think of
darkness what picture comes to your mind
if you've seen thick darkness before but
I want you to try to visualize this
darkness as nothing you've ever seen
before like nothing you've ever seen
before
this is a thick impenetrable darkness
that the children of Israel are
beholding all right and they are
terrified of it they don't understand it
this is the darkness of God the darkness
of God well let's go on and look at what
Deuteronomy chapter 4 tells us Gudrun
before 11 speaking about this experience
it says and you came near and stood
under the mountain and the mountain
burned with fire unto the midst of
heaven with darkness clouds and thick
darkness again I want you to imagine
this darkness like nothing you have ever
seen before verse 12 and the Lord spake
unto you out of the midst of the fire
you heard the voice of the words but you
saw no similar tune only you heard a
voice and he declared unto you his
covenant which he commanded you to
perform even ten commandments and he
wrote them upon two tables of stone now
this is very interesting because at
Mount Sinai this is where God gives to
the children of Israel the Ten
Commandments right he's speaking these
Commandments from the midst of this
thick impenetrable incomprehensible
darkness he speaks the law of God food
now you might be thinking whom
love God impenetrable darkness like when
I think of darkness I think of you know
gloominess I think of sin I think of
everything that is dark and here God is
speaking the law of God from this
darkness now what is first John chapter
3 verse 4 tell us first John chapter 3
verse 4 says this who super committed
sin transgresses also the law for sin is
the transgression of the law
did you catch that sin is the
transgression of the law
now what is Romans 6:23 tell us the
Bible says for the wages of sin is what
death the wages of sin is death I'm just
gonna pause right there so we might be
tempted to think this dark cloud where
God is speaking his law from right
anyone who transgresses this law is
doomed to death so this darkness of God
this dark cloud must be a warning
against the sinner and that's why the
people are afraid but I want you to just
pause for a second we're gonna come back
to that and check out Psalm chapter 18
verse 11 in some 18 verse 11 listen to
what the Bible says here it says
speaking of God he made darkness his
secret place pause for a second guys the
Bible says God makes darkness his secret
place his pavilion round about him were
dark waters and thick clouds of the
skies so check this out now his pavilion
now what is his pavilion give me another
word for pavilion what would his
pavilion be if you said the word tent
you're spot on because a pavilion that's
what it is God's tent or his secret
place is darkness around him dark waters
check this out guys dark waters and
big clouds of the skies this is what God
makes his a this is how God makes his
secret place now when you hear the term
secret place what do you think of most
of you if not all of you should be
thinking the sanctuary so hold on a
second
God makes his sanctuary a dark place how
does that even make sense how does that
I don't understand pastor what are you
trying to say how is God making darkness
his sanctuary his secret place all right
hold that thought I know you've got
questions but just hold that thought
we're gonna go to the book of Exodus
chapter 40 and in Exodus chapter 40 God
it Moses has just finished building the
sanctuary the children of Israel along
with Moses have just completed the
sanctuary and I want you to notice what
happens in verses 34 and 35 the Bible
says then a cloud and if you look up in
the Strong's Concordance it's describing
a Nimbus cloud a thunderous cloud a dark
cloud right so then a cloud a dark cloud
covered the tent of the congregation and
the glory of the Lord filled the
tabernacle and Moses was not able to
enter into the tent of the congregation
because the cloud abode thereon and the
glory of the Lord filled the tabernacle
the glory of the Lord is synonymous with
this dark impenetrable incomprehensible
cloud a cloud so thick that it could not
be entered I hope you're catching what
I'm saying it's made of mace it make
sense to you now but just follow along
because something amazing is coming here
I'm gonna go to first Kings chapter 8
because the same thing happens when
Solomon builds his temple in first Kings
chapter 8 verse 10 the Bible says here
and it came to pass when the priests
were come out of the holy place that the
cloud
filled the house of the Lord so that the
priest could not stand to Minister
because of the cloud for the glory of
the Lord had filled the house of the
Lord and now notice verse 12 then spake
Solomon the Lord said that he would
dwell in thick darkness so how is
Solomon describing this cloud that fill
the temple it was a cloud of darkness of
thick darkness all right so we just saw
the children of Israel when they saw
this dark cloud they were terrified they
were afraid they didn't understand the
cloud we see that when the cloud comes
down and fills the tabernacle nobody can
enter because the cloud is so thick it
this is an impenetrable cloud a dark
cloud in fact one of the words used to
describe this cloud this word cloud is
gloomy all right hold those thoughts and
I want you to check out this next verse
Psalm 97 verse 1 the Bible says here the
Lord reigneth let the earth rejoice
alright so everybody should do what
everyone rejoice rejoice rejoice yes the
Lord reigns let the earth rejoice why
let the multitude of the Isles be glad
thereof and I'll check out this next
verse clouds and darkness are round
about him righteousness and judgment are
the habitation of his throne hold on
wait a minute
so I'm supposed to rejoice I'm supposed
to rejoice because the Lord reigns
because clouds and darkness are round
about him wait a minute darkness and
thick clouds doesn't seem like a very
rejoice a very rejoiceful type of thing
doesn't feel like something I should
rejoice about but the Bible says rejoice
and it goes on to say look clouds and
dark
around about him hmm why should
something that appears so dark so thick
so foreboding so gloomy so terrifying
lead us to rejoice what is this thick
darkness and why is it found in the
sanctuary why is it his secret place all
right put a pause and all that right
there and now we're gonna switch gears
just for a moment because I want to
we're not really switching gears I'm
just gonna take you to a whole nother
text is gonna show you something from a
totally different angle but you will see
how this ties in in a moment come with
me to the Book of Leviticus Leviticus
chapter 12 and I'm gonna begin reading
from verse 1 and I want you to listen
carefully the Bible says and the Lord
spake unto Moses saying speak unto the
children of Israel sing if a woman have
conceived seed and borne a man-child I
want you to remember that trees
man-child it's only used maybe around
seven or eight times in the entire bible
and most of those are in the Old
Testament it is used once maybe twice in
the New Testament but I want you to
listen carefully if a woman have
conceived seed and born a man-child then
she shall be unclean seven days
according to the days of a separation
for her infirmity she shall be unclean
and in the eighth day of the flesh of of
his foreskin he shall be circumcised
this is the man child was to be
circumcised on the eighth day
now I'm notice verse four and then shall
then she shall continue in the blood of
her purifying three and thirty days she
shall touch no how about thing nor come
into the sanctuary until the days of her
purifying be full filled all right let
me explain if a woman was to have a
man-child
she was basically unclean
for 33 days for 33 days she could not
come into the sanctuary 30 I'm sorry
yes 33 days 33 days I'm about to jump
ahead of myself here so check this out a
woman having a man-child was to be
unclean for 33 days at the end of that
33 days
Leviticus 12 verse 6 when the days of
her purifying are fulfilled for a son of
for daughter she shall bring a lamb of
the first year for a burnt offering and
a young pigeon or a turtle dove for sin
offering unto the door of a tabernacle
of the congregation unto the priest who
shall offer it before the Lord and shall
make an atonement for her and she shall
be cleansed from her issue of blood so
let me break this down for you
if a woman had a man-child she was to be
unclean for 33 days at the end of the 33
days a sacrifice was made by which she
now had access to the sanctuary
hmm-hmm-hmm-hmm if you're following this
just respond so I can see okay
why is this crucial to understand in the
book of Revelation chapter 12 the Bible
describes a scene here that will now
jump off the page to you because in
Revelation 12 verse 1 the Bible says
there appeared a great wonder in heaven
a woman clothed with the Sun and the
moon under her feet and upon her head a
crown of 12 stars now who is this woman
we know this woman to represent the
church hold on the Bible says in verse 2
and she being with child cried
travailing in birth and pained to be
delivered so this woman is pregnant
verse 3 and there appeared another
wonder in heaven and behold a great red
dragon having seven heads and ten horns
and seven Crown's upon his head verse
four and his tail drew the third part of
the stars of heaven and did cast into
the earth and the dragon stood before
the woman which was to be delivered for
it
devour her child as soon as it was born
so this woman is having a child and the
dragon is trying to destroy this child
now notice in the next verse and she
brought forth what what does he bring
forth every one she brought forth a man
child this is the only time that term
man child is used in the New Testament
here you have a woman who is pregnant
who brings forth a man child who was to
rule all nations with a rod of iron and
her child was caught up to God and to
his throne all right so we know that
this child represents who yes yes it
represents Jesus Christ amen and I got
another question for you how long was it
before Jesus was caught up onto God's
throne hmm what did you say he said 33
years didn't you 33 years yes at the end
of that 33 years what happened was there
a sacrifice made absolutely there was a
sacrifice made and that sacrifice was
Jesus Christ the Lamb of God now
according to the Book of Leviticus
chapter 12 if a woman having a male
child when a woman has a man-child she's
unclean for how long 33 days at the end
of which there was a sacrifice made and
that sacrifice gives her access to the
temple boy I hope you see this guy's
access to the temple when Jesus Christ
died for our sins in fact let me let
Hebrews tell it to us Hebrews chapter 10
verse 19 having therefore brethren
boldness to enter into the holiest by
the blood of Jesus by a new and living
way which he has consecrated for us
through the veil that is to say his
flesh and having a high priest over the
house of God let us draw near with a
true heart in full assurance of faith
having
hearts sprinkled from an evil conscience
and our bodies washed with pure water so
watch this guys well the Bible is
telling us in the book of Hebrews is
that with the death burial and
resurrection of Jesus the church now has
boldness to enter into the secret place
of the Most High the sanctuary the
sanctuary that is located in heaven now
here's my question for you why would we
need boldness to enter I want you to
think about that why would we need
boldness to enter yeah yeah yeah yeah
you're getting this now right because
what did God say about his secret place
what did God say about his sanctuary he
said about his sanctuary that it is
darkness big darkness incomprehensible
darkness so why would God be inviting us
into thick darkness into
incomprehensible darkness why is he
doing that
why is he inviting his church his people
into this darkness
that's a good question that's a good
question probably I think I know what
verse you guys may be thinking of right
now and let's just go there Psalm 91 in
Psalm 91 the Bible says he that dwelleth
in the where in the where that's right
guys he that dwelleth in the secret
place of the Most High shall abide under
the Watts yes yes under the shadow of
the Almighty
what is the shadow of the Almighty what
is that darkness of the what is that
shade of the Almighty it is that thick
darkness bit of it listen what it says
those who dwell in this thick darkness I
will save the Lord he is my refuge and
my fortress ah wait a minute wait a
minute pastor are you telling me that
that thick darkness is actually meant to
be our fortress our protection
absolutely absolutely
you see but I mean that thick darkness
is designed so that no weapon formed
against you can get to you that darkness
is is is designed to keep the enemies of
God out and terrified from coming after
you and I'm talking specifically about
the ark enemy of God Satan himself this
is why the Bible says surely he shall
deliver thee from the snare of the
Fowler and from the noisome pestilence
he will cover thee with the feathers of
with his feathers and under his wings
shalt trust his truth shall be thy
shield and buckler thou shalt not be
afraid for the terror by night nor for
the arrow that flies by day nor for the
pestilence that walketh in darkness nor
for the destruction that wasteth at
noonday beloved listen to me that
darkness of God is meant to be your
protection that darkness of God is meant
to keep you safe remember when the
children of Israel were being pursued by
the Egyptians remember what God put
between the Egyptians and the children
of Israel he put between them a cloud
now to the enemies it was darkness but
to the people of God it was light
[Music]
are you catching this guys are you
catching this idea
you see Psalm 27 verse 4 and 5 puts it
even more clearly here's what it says
one thing have I desired of the Lord
that will I seek after that I may dwell
in the house of the Lord all the days of
my life to behold the beauty of the Lord
and to enquire in his temple notice
verse 5 for in the time of trouble he
shall hide me whoa hi what he saw hide
me in his pavilion in the secret of his
Tabernacle shall he hide me he shall set
me upon a rock so what it why does God
make darkness his secret place because
but other because it is in that darkness
that he protects his people from
anything the enemy can bring them yes in
the time of trouble he hides me he hides
me in a place that is so dark that is so
thick that the enemies of God that the
enemy that Satan himself cannot enter it
how many of you appreciate the secret
place of the Most High
how many of you appreciate the fact that
God so desires to protect us that he
says listen man I'm gonna make this
thing so thick I'm gonna make this thing
so dark I'm gonna make this thing so
incomprehensible so impenetrable that
nothing will be able to come at you yes
whatever the darkness of God
you should be rejoicing at the darkness
of God listen Psalm 51 Psalm 51
David cries out have mercy upon me O God
according to thy loving-kindness
according to the multitude of thy tender
mercies blot out my transgressions I'm
about to show you another angle of this
dark cloud beloved because God says
David says blot out my transgressions
does God answer yes he does and I want
you to notice how he answers notice with
me Isaiah 44 verse 22 hey you want your
sins blotted out watch this God says I
have blotted out as or what as I what
guys come on I need you to say it I know
I can't hear you but I just need you to
say this out loud
God has blotted out I have thought about
as a what yes yes yes I get it now as a
thick cloud God uses that thick cloud as
a sin
of his mercy to block sins out yes I
have blotted out as a thick cloud thy
transgressions and as a cloud thy sins
return unto me for I have redeemed thee
sing o ye heavens for the Lord has done
it Southie lower parts of the earth
break forth into singing e-mount ins of
forests and every tree therein for the
Lord has redeemed Jacob and glorified
himself in Israel why did God come to
Israel in a thick cloud because he was
saying listen I'm giving you my law but
I want you to know that I'm also a God
of mercy and I'm coming to you in this
thick cloud so that you can know that
when you ask for forgiveness for
breaking my law I will bring your sins
into this thick cloud so that you cannot
find them I will bring this sin into
this I will bring your confessed sins
into this thick cloud so that your sins
cannot be found yes yes yes rejoice
rejoice about the dark cloud of God
rejoice about the darkness of God
rejoice because listen no one can
penetrate your forgiving sins no one can
use your sins against you no one can
condemn you no one can reach into that
cloud and grab sins that God has
forgiven you of beloved listen to me you
need to trust in the darkness of that
cloud you need to trust that God loves
you so much that he says I'm gonna
represent my power to hide your sins to
to get rid of your sins as a thick and
dark cloud that no one can penetrate
Amen Psalm 19 Psalm 19 listen beloved
the Bible says Psalm 19 verse 12 who can
understand his errors cleanse down me
from what kind of faults from what kind
of thoughts from what
secret faults so if I want to get rid of
my secret faults I've got two options I
can either keep it keep it secret within
myself which the devil is gonna have
easy access to people are gonna have
easy access to or I can give over my
secret faults to God and God takes those
secret faults because I've asked for
forgiveness God takes those secret
faults God takes those things in which
we struggle in our hearts those things
that no one wants to share with anyone
God says I will take those as listen you
know you know whose secrets are for who
do you tell secrets to who do you tell
your most trusted secrets to I'm just
talking about on a purely secular level
you tell your secrets to the people you
trust the most you tell your secrets to
best friends you know what God is doing
here he's saying listen I want to be
your best friend tell me your secrets I
promise you
give me your secrets and I will I will
block those secrets out and I will not
spread your secret I will not prove it
I will keep your bring it to the secret
place bring it to the secret place God
says I will keep it secret there why
here's why he's gonna keep it secret
there Bible says in Micah 7:19 who is a
God like unto thee that pardon if
iniquity and passes by the transgression
of the of the remnant of his hair of his
heritage he retains not his anger
forever because he delights in mercy he
will turn again he will have compassion
upon us he will subdue our iniquities
and that will cast all all their sins
into the depth of the sea
remember how God described his sanctuary
thick clouds and dark waters dark waters
praise God for dark waters because God
says that's my secret place
thick clouds dark waters I'm gonna take
your sins and I'm gonna put them in
thick clouds dark waters so that they
cannot be found they love it listen to
me the human heart has a problem with
guilt we have a problem with wrestling
with has God really forgiven me can God
truly accept me can i really make it
into heaven listen to let me tell you
them I believe that by the grace of God
when we all get to heaven and Jesus is
like enter thou into my kingdom I think
we're all gonna be like I think we're
gonna be looking at each other like is
he short like does he know that I mean
we know he knows another is what I'm
saying beloved is that it is only by the
grace of God that we get none of us will
enter Heaven saying yeah I got here and
I deserve to be here all of us everyone
who will make it to heaven everyone who
makes it to heaven will realize that it
is only by the grace of God that we are
there that it is only because of that
thick darkness that we are there and God
is making this very simple for us guys
all he's saying is listen give me your
secrets give me your give me your sins
bring me your secret faults confess them
to me and I will take them and I will
separate you from them and I will hide
those sins in the darkness of my
presence how many of you like in that
fake darkness right now how many of your
thinking right now a man praise God for
the fake darkness praise God for the
thick darkness bill of it listen to me
I want you to see this you see in the
Old Testament only listen carefully guys
in the Old Testament no I could gaze
into the most holy place where the
presence of God was no I could gaze into
only the eye of the high priest was
allowed to look into the most holy place
no one else could
are you rejoicing right now nobody else
could see into the place where the
presence of God was only the high priest
are you rejoicing right now are you are
you catching what I'm saying right now
let me try to explain it this way so in
the Old Testament when you commit a sin
you know you're in your home you commit
a sin your whole family knows about the
sin right and it's embarrassing because
they all know your faults and your
failures but then you have to go to the
sanctuary and you have to lay your knob
just imagine people in those days
they're looking and they're watching you
walk to the sanctuary and they're like
yeah I must have done something he's
just done something we don't know we may
not know what it is but he's done
something so eyes were on your sin you
you you put your head on the your hands
on the head of that animal you confess
your sins right and you got all these
eyes on you and it's embarrassing but
from that point that that's the outer
court that's where you did that from
that point fewer people the priest took
your sin into the holy place the blood
was taken into the holy place and it
wasn't just a high priest there were
other priests priests that could go into
the holy place and take your sin in so
less eyes but listen only the high
priest could go into the most holy place
or let's say the secret place of the
Most High
only the eyes of the high priest could
take the sins could
see into the most holy place but love it
let me put it this way know I can
penetrate the darkness of God except the
eye of Jesus only Jesus Jesus says I
will take your sins and those sins will
be nobody else's business there are the
business of me and my heavenly father
and when you ask for forgiveness of sins
God says I'm taking it out of the eyes
of everyone out of the business of
everyone and I'm taking it into the most
holy place where it will be in thick
darkness and only my eyes know why is
this important to understand because you
see Satan wants you to doubt the power
of God's forgiveness he wants you to
doubt the darkness of God is it really
that dark can it be see you know what
Satan's called in Revelation chapter 12
verse 10 I want to do this and this and
I heard a voice from heaven saying in
heaven now is come salvation and
strength and the Kingdom of our God and
the power of his Christ for the accuser
of our brethren is cast down which
accused them before our God day and
night Satan's job is to continue to
bring your sins before you is to make
you believe that they have not been
dissolved in the dark cloud is to make
you believe that God has not truly
forgiven you
that's what Satan's job is and sometimes
Satan will use people to assist him did
you did you hear what I just said
sometimes Satan will use people to a
system Psalm 31 verse 20 this is why the
Bible says thou shalt hide them in the
secret of thy presence from the pride of
man and thou shalt keep them secretly in
a pavilion from the strife of tongues so
check out what God is saying here God is
saying listen I'm going to keep you in
my secret place
I'm gonna keep you protect you in my
secret pavilion from the strife of
tongues what is the strife of tongues
what is the strife of tongues its people
what talking and people are putting you
down and people making you feel like
yeah you're not good enough for God the
voice of Satan speaking in your mind
saying you're not good enough for God
God can't forgive you you've done too
much look at what you're going through
in life right now look surely God has
forsaken you but loving let me ask a
question do the righteous suffer yes
they do do the righteous get poor yes
they do do the righteous lose jobs yes
they do do the righteous get sick yes
they do but love it listen to me don't
allow your current circumstances to
dictate to you whether you have a
relationship with God or not or whether
God loves you or not because all we got
to do is look at the cross then God
loved his son Jesus yes and guess what
what he went through on the cross is way
way WAY worse way worse than anything
you and I can experience did God love
his son yes he did yes he did and and oh
man I I'm tempted to jump ahead right
now I might just jump ahead a little bit
do you remember what happened when Jesus
died on the cross just before he died
what came down upon the earth what what
do you say I couldn't hear you
Oh what is it oh yes thick darkness all
right hold that thought
let's just keep moving check this out
I'm gonna come back to that thought so
do not fear
proverbs 10 verse 12 hatred stirs up
strife but love hatred stir let's go
back to the verse before thou shalt thou
shalt hide them in the secret place of
thy presence from the pride of man thou
shalt keep them secretly in a pavilion
from the strife of tongues now the next
verse problems 1012
hatred stirred up stripes when people
hate you they're going to try to do all
kinds of things against you and in the
church that means they're gonna try to
make it appear that you're not really
saved that you don't really have a
relationship with God that's what Satan
does and if it's not people in the
church it's Satan speaking to you in
your own mind
it's the strife of his tones his voice
speaking to you but notice the next part
of this verse love covers all sins so
hold on pastor what are you saying that
dark cloud is a symbol of God's love
what if the dark cloud do what does the
dark cloud do yes it blots out it covers
it brings into darkness your confessed
sins don't get me wrong
not unconfessed sins don't think that
God covers unconfessed sins unconfessed
sins our sins you want to hold on to I'm
gonna keep these secret to myself I'm
not sharing them with you God but
confess sins the Bible says love covers
all sins so if the dark cloud is
covering your sin because you confessed
it beloved that dark cloud becomes a
symbol of God's love I hope you're
feeling this guy's proverbs 1113 a tail
bearer reveal secrets but he that is of
a faithful spirit
feels the matter what is God saying to
us hey I am one that will I'm not out to
embarrass you I'm out to shame you I
want you to know that I will conceal all
your sins if you simply confess that
they were wrong bring them to me and I
will keep it between me and you I will I
will throw those sins into the depth of
the sea and and woe unto the man or the
woman or the angel that tries to enter
into the secret place of the Most High
to gather sins to bring them back out
and bring shame upon God's people hmm
Wow be careful Church be careful be
careful when you condemn people and
don't know what's in their hearts be
careful yeah you know what we've all
been guilty of that yes yes yes we've
all been guilty of that and check it out
when we're guilty of that you know what
we're doing we are entering into the
secret place of the Most High
looking for sins and listen carefully
only the high priest could enter the
secret place of the Most High for that
purpose so when you do that guess who
you're acting like guess who you're
claiming to be yes yeah you're claiming
the prerogatives of God only who can
read the heart
Psalm 64 verse 2 and I want you to
notice what it says here
Psalm 64 verse 2 hide me from the secret
counsel of the wicked from the
insurrection of the workers of iniquity
who went their tongue like a like a
sword and bend their bows to shoot their
arrows even bitter words that they may
shoot in secret at the perfect suddenly
they do shoot at him and fear not they
encourage themselves in an evil matter
they commune of laying snares privily
they say who shall see them watch this
next verse they search out iniquities
they accomplish a diligent search both
the inward thought of every one of them
and the heart is the what are they doing
they are
searching out iniquity now beloved
listen to me when you do that you are
doing something that has been reserved
for the Millennium the 1000 year
millennium because it is during the
1,000 year but and I'll come to this
later but it is during that time that
judgment is given unto the Saints
judgment is not now given unto the
Saints why because we don't have access
to the secret place of the Most High for
the purpose of judging other people's
sins we can't see them God keeps them
secret if you want to enter the secret
place of the Most High it's to hide
yourself did you catch what I said is to
hide yourself but many people are
entering in trying to get into the
secret place of the Most High in other
words you are bringing up you are
condemning people who you have no right
to condemn and beloved i'ma share some
with you that's why it is really
important to just watch your tongue I'm
not saying don't judge fruit you know by
their fruit you shall know them that's
not what I'm saying but when you talk
about judging a person's intent and
judging a person's heart you're on
dangerous ground because you don't know
what God is doing in a person's heart so
does that mean that you shouldn't call a
thief a thief the guy just stole
something but I don't want to call him a
thief because that's judging no no no no
that's the wrong idea of judging judging
is looking at someone and saying I bet
you that person is probably a thief
you have no outward evidence that the
person as such that's what I'm talking
about that's why God says don't judge in
that particular sense do not judge
because you're trying to do a work that
only that belongs to God and a work that
he gives to his Saints only at the end
of only during the Millennium all right
so watch this guy's
if love covers a multitude of sins if
the darkness if the dark cloud is a
symbol of God's love I want you to catch
then I want you to catch then what
happens at the death of Jesus because in
Matthew 27 verse 45 the Bible says now
from the sixth hour there was darkness
over all the land until the ninth hour
Wow Wow guys what why is darkness
covering the earth because of this very
thing beloved this is a manifestation of
the love of God he could have destroyed
the earth for killing his son but
instead like a thick cloud he descends
upon the earth extending revealing the
great mercies of the God of heaven yeah
what does the Bible say God is what God
is love God is love I want you to check
this out love it psalm 32 verse 1
blessed is he whose transgression is
forgiven whose sin is covered
that's what the dark cloud is for God
invites us to bring our sins into the
secret place so that to send our sins
into the secret place so that they may
be covered first Peter 4:8 the Bible
says here for charity that means love
love shall cover a multitude of sins
that's what love does how many of you
remember that story that crazy story in
the Bible of Noah Shem ham and candy
remember that story where Noah does
something stupid he gets drunk Noah the
man of God gets drunk let me ask you do
we all have failures when I was on live
last night watching
I see Southwest and my good friend Peter
Chung just started in on this going down
the list of all the people in the Bible
who like who messed up and it was Noah
David Abraham all the people of God that
messed up and yet God extended mercy
powerful powerful thought here Noah is
he's drunk and and ham comes it I'm not
ham oh boy
mom having a brain freeze right now the
youngest son comes in you know who I'm
talking about and he looks at his he
looks at his at his father and he mocks
his father Shem comes in and what a Shem
do the Bible says that Shem turned
around and walked backward and covered
his father's nakedness and Shem received
the blessing of the genealogy of Jesus
in other words beloved what Shem did was
a type of what Jesus did for us at the
cross Jesus covers our sins he is not
out there trying to expose our sins he
is trying to cover them because that's
what love does love covers a multitude
of sins now I want you to check this out
Rick we are almost towards the end guys
we're almost there check this out guys
in psalm or in isaiah 32 and isaiah 32
verse 1 the Bible says here behold a
king shall reign in righteousness and
princes shall judge shall rule in
judgment Isaiah 32 verse 2 and a man
shall be as a hiding place from the wind
and the covert from the tempest as
rivers of water in a dry place and as
the shadow of a great rock in a weary
land the Bible says here a man shall be
as a hiding place and a covert from the
tempest what man what man yes you got it
that man is Jesus
and that's why Jesus himself becomes a
symbol or a type of the century you
remember he said destroy this temple and
I will raise it again in three days
in other words beloved in Jesus Christ
we may hide our sins he is our secret
place Colossians 3:3 says for you are
dead and your life is hid with Christ in
God did you catch that did you catch
that Christ is our hiding place that's
why when we come to him and confess our
sins he takes our sins and he and he and
he does something with them that no
human power can do he brings them into
the thick dark cloud of his own glory of
his own presence now the darkness of God
symbolizes his love forgiveness and
mercy so watch this guys I'm getting
ready to close oh you are you ready for
this I hope you're ready for this watch
this Revelation 1:7 tells us that when
Jesus comes again he's coming with the
clouds look in Revelation 1:7 behold he
comes with the clouds and every eye so
what's he coming with he's coming with
clouds I'm asking a question what kind
of cloud you think he's coming with for
those of you who are students of
prophecy you know that when Jesus comes
again he's coming on what appears at
first to be a dark cloud you know dark
calm small small dark cloud
and the people who see this small dark
cloud recognize it as the symbol of God
that's God right there why do they know
that that dark cloud is gone you got it
they know the dark cloud is God because
they are familiar with the forgiveness
and murder they are familiar with it as
the symbol of God's mercy and
forgiveness are you feeling these guys
are you catching this
so notice Psalm 18 Psalm 18 this is not
next to last verse
the Bible says speaking of God he bowed
the heavens also and came down and
darkness was under his feet so this is
talking about this is actually
translated a dark cloud was under his
feet he bowed the heavens also and came
down and darkness or dark clouds were
under his feet so when Jesus comes down
when God comes again he's coming with a
dark cloud or watch this he rode upon a
cherub and did fly yay he did fly upon
the wings of the wind
he made darkness his secret place his
pavilion round about him were at
Dartmouth more dark waters and thick
clouds from the skies now watch this
next verse at the brightness that was
before him his thick clouds past pause
for a second let me rephrase that text
for you what it's telling us is that at
his brightness the thick clouds
eventually dissipate those thick clouds
will turn to a white cloud so when Jesus
comes again first it appears as a dark
cloud but as he comes closer and the
cloud gets bigger the cloud begins to
turn white what is that symbol telling
us for the redeemed they will see it as
this here is the one who took our sins
and hid them in the depths of the sea
forgave us and watch this made us white
as snow
isaiah 1:16 wash you make you
put away the evil of your doings from
before mine eyes cease to do evil learn
to do well seek judgment relieve the
oppressed judge the fatherless plead for
the widow come now and let us reason
together save the Lord though your sins
be as scarlet they shall be as white as
snow though they be red like crimson
they shall be as wool when Jesus comes
again that dark cloud turns to a white
cloud and the people of God will
recognize that as the mercy of God that
here is the one who took my sins brought
them into his secret place cast them
into the depth of the sea and has now
made me white as snow
yes beloved it is true God is love no
matter what you're going through right
now God is love no matter what the
circumstances are around you if you're
confessing your sins to God if you're
praying to God you might not be in the
best of health you might not be in the
best of financial situations you might
not be in the best of various situations
but beloved if you are giving your sins
to God yes even listen you may be
failing and faltering and oh I'm messed
up again today God if you're giving your
sins to God and I don't want to make
this seem like all you have to do you
don't have to worry about living a
better life I'm simply saying if you are
genuine and honest about trying to serve
God and giving him your sins and trying
to try to walk the better life in his
power and in His grace beloved I want
you to understand this do not let your
circumstances trick you or fool you into
thinking that God has not heard you or
that God has not forgiven your sins
beloved God
is love God is is Oh Heavenly Father we
want to thank you Lord for the dark
cloud we want to thank you for the
darkness that you call the secret place
because their Lord we can bring our sins
to you their Lord we can bring our
faults to you and Lord you take them and
you take those forgiven and confess sins
and cover them in such darkness that no
one can find them and Lord we thank you
because woe unto those who seek to enter
your darkness to hold your people down
for confessing this is what Satan does
he will continually seek to bring our
faults before our eyes but Lord let us
trust in you let us trust in that secret
place Lord please forgive us for
doubting your love forgive us for
doubting your mercy forgive us for
doubting your grace we thank you Lord
for that amazing grace we thank you for
that amazing love Lord take our sins and
cast them into the depth of that cloud
of that sea and Lord make us white as
snow
this is our prayer in the precious and
holy name of Jesus amen and amen
[Music]
keep all I can know you will be soldier
view my miles until you make it home
don't give up until the fight is over
promise that you'll never walk alone
when you wander through the silence
see you Nami coming for your soul I
stand between now be your shield guide
cause my love for you so deep in one
deep and ride on my love for you it's so
deep and wide I will lead you till you
find the garden in your darkest moment
help you see oh that in depth you will
become the living office aching you will
be made free and I will write your name
upon the heaven I will give you all the
turning lets me I gave my life to write
the final chapter all imagination still
can't see you're just I'm deep in right
deep lies oh my love for you it's so
deep in wide deep deep
[Music]
d God so loved the world and he died
deep away
Jesus lovely star even it's even death
he couldn't hold him
[Music]
you